Kriti Sharma

Dayton, Ohio, USA | LinkedIn | +1 9377016244 | kritisharma1778@gmail.com | Website

SUMMARY

Problem-solving, empathetic, and conscientious computer science graduate student with a demonstrated history of 3 years, working in the IT industry. Skilled in Development, Cloud, Data & Analytics. Analytic performer who enjoys finding solutions to high impact issues. Proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science
University of Dayton, Current GPA-4.0/4.0
Bachelor of Technology (Hons), Computer Science
Uttarakhand Technical University, GPA-3.2/4.0

Ohio, USA Aug 2022–May 2024 Uttarakhand, India Aug 2015-July 2019

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages/Libraries: Python, Pandas, NumPy, HTML **Databases**: MySQL, Azure Cosmos, Azure Table Storage, Azure SQL

Data/Query Language: Kusto, Scope Query Language, SQL, Data Mining, Data Visualization, Data Transformation **Technology/Services:** Azure Data Factory, Azure Data Lake, Azure Synapse Analytics, ETL, Azure Batch, Azure Blob **Tools:** Visual Studio, PyCharm, Power BI, Jupyter Notebook, Azure Data Explorer, Azure Data Studio, Git, Azure DevOps

EXPERIENCE

Mindtree, Azure Data Engineer Microsoft BIT Research, Microsoft

September 2019 – July 2022 | Pune, India Oct 2020 – July 2022

- Led the migration of all the scheduled jobs from legacy portal to Azure Data Factory, resulting in an annual 30 percent cost savings and performance increase.
- Built web scraper in python to acquire data from different sources and implemented an ETL with various components like pipeline, activity, mapping data flows, linked services and control flows.
- Designed and implemented real time data pipeline to process semi structured data by integrating 100 million raw records from 20 + data sources using U-SQL Azure, Azure Cosmos Db, and Azure Data Factory.
- Used Kusto Explorer for log analytics, better query response and created alerts using Kusto Query Language.
- Worked with REST APIs to retrieve analytics data from different data feeds.
- Worked with clients to understand business needs and translate those into actionable reports in Power BI, saving almost 13 hours of manual work each week.

Microsoft Digital Operation Services, Microsoft

Sept 2019 – Sept 2020

- Created SQL queries and stored procedures to handle and maintaining relational database.
- Led data extraction, transformation, and aggregation from multiple file formats for analyzing & transforming.
- Worked on SSMS, Azure Table Storage to fetch/update the data according to the customer requirements.
- Created design documents for new features and enhancement and weekly reports for analysis.
- Have good experience in tracking and logging end to end software application build using Azure DevOps.
- Developed JSON Scripts for deploying the Pipeline in ADF that process the data using the ADF Activity.
- Headed the cross-team trainings and knowledge transfers.

Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee, Intern

July 2018- Sep 2018 | Roorkee, India

Prediction of Forest Fires, in state Uttarakhand, India

- Created Machine Learning model using real time series analysis to predict the occurrences.
- Trained machine using past fire occurrences and climatic data from Environment information System.
- Achieved 93 percent accuracy using Logistic Regression and Clustering.
- Transformed and cleaned data using pandas and NumPy library.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft: AZ-900 Azure Data Fundamentals
- LinkedIn: Data Analysis using Power BI
- Data Analysis, Complete Bootcamp